David Arrowsmith

linkedin email

Introduction

I'm a software engineer experienced in web development with JavaScript and related technologies.

I currently work as a Frontend Developer at Twentysix, a digital agency with a diverse portfolio of clients. I help deliver CMS-driven projects such as websites, digital sales aids and training tools.

I work part-time at Manchester Codes, a software development school. I teach JavaScript fundamentals and frontend development with React.

Skills

```
CSS Docker Express Figma Git Handlebars Heroku HTML Lighthouse JavaScript

Jest Jira Mocha MongoDB Mongoose MySQL Node.JS React React Testing Library

SASS Sequelize Styled Components Supertest TypeScript VS Code Vue WAVE Xd
```

Experience

Frontend Developer

Twentysix | December 2021 - Present

I deliver frontend solutions as part of a close multidisciplinary team.

Responsibilities:

- Implement designs to specification, as defined in Jira tickets and Xd / Figma designs.
- Follow accessibility best practices. Raise accessibility concerns.
- Utilise a variety of contemporary & legacy frameworks including React, Vue, Handlebars, Bootstrap & JOuery.
- Create CMS templates to test frontend solutions (Optimisely, Strapi, Umbraco).
- Follow project-specific Git protocols. Maintain a succinct and descriptive commit history for user-friendly version control.
- Perform code reviews.
- Communicate openly with the project manager and wider team, promptly raising questions and issues.
- Participate in refinements, estimations and planning meetings (internal and client-facing).
- Host team rituals such as stand-ups and retrospectives.
- Engage in discussions about upcoming technologies and process improvements.
- Help onboard new starters.
- Assist colleagues with technical issues.
- Organize ~fortnightly Lunch & Learns.

Tutor (Software Development)

Manchester Codes | January 2022 - Present

Manchester Codes is a software development school. I help deliver their Software Developer Fast Track course, which focusses on web development using JavaScript and related technologies.

Responsibilities:

• Deliver lectures in the following modules:

Core: Development environment setup, Tooling, Git, HTML, CSS & Javascript **Frontend:** React, Component-based design, Data management, Advanced styling

- Create new lectures consisting of presentations, demonstrations and workshops
- Create GitHub repos for student experimentation
- Support students via Slack
- · Update content on the learning platform
- Participate in internal discussions about course content and the school's direction

Foundation Software Developer

Thinkmoney | July 2021 - December 2021

I joined Thinkmoney under their Foundation Developer programme, which combined practical development work with a three-month training programme.

Responsibilities:

- Apply updates and bugfixes to the Thinkmoney mobile application.
- Participate in refinements and estimations.
- Participate in group training workshops.
- Complete OutSystems training courses within allocated timeframes.

Senior Research & Development Chemist

Sherwin Williams P&MC | February 2018 - July 2021

Prior to my career as a software developer I worked as a research chemist. At Sherwin-Williams I developed novel functional coatings (paint) for use in heavy industries such as oil & gas refinement, shipping and infrastructure.

Education

- Software Development Fast-Track
 Manchester Codes | March September 2021
- Chemistry MSc by Research
 University of Manchester | 2016 2017
- Chemistry BSc
 University of Liverpool | 2006 2010